<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.ruleml.org/homepage.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!-- Written by Harold Boley -->
<homepage>
	<title>eTourPlan</title>
	<opening>
		<center>
			<br/>
			<!--<a href="http://www.ruleml.org"><img src="http://www.ruleml.org/logo/rulemllogo2_transparent.gif" border="none" alt="RuleML"/></a>-->
			<br/>
			<h1>eTourPlan<br/>
				<i>A Knowledge-Based Tourist Route and Activity Planner</i>
			</h1>
			  <h2>Harold Boley, Przemyslaw Rafal Pochec, Tshering Dema
			  </h2>
                  <h4>Version History, 2008-09-09: Version 0.1
                  </h4>
			<br/>
			

		</center>
		<br/>

	</opening>
	<section>
		<header>Overview</header>
		<p>Tourism is the world's largest and fastest growing industry. There are many conventional
tourism service providers which are competitively trying to provide the best travel plans
and recommendations to customers based on their interests. The Semantic Web is a major
endeavour to enhance the Web by enriching its content with semantic (meta)data that can
be processed by inference-enabled Web applications. eTourism is a prime candidate for
such enrichment, since it is an information-based business. As with any such business,
providing the required relevant information for the consumer means a better end product.
Thus, providing a well-structured and comprehensive Knowledge Base (KB) for consulting
will help bolster eTourism business. We have designed and implemented a KB
consisting of tourism domain-specific information. Our KB stores facts about Bhutan, which
are structured by a light-weight ontology (adapted from the Harmonise eTourism ontology)
and used by partonomy rules that encode the geographical partitioning of tourist regions
and provide a basis for activity search capabilities. On top of these, the KB’s planning rules
are applied to deduce recommendations of routes, activities (attractions and events), and
accommodations. We also discussed transferring Friend Of A Friend (FOAF) concepts
for semantically describing persons or organizations, to tourist-entity profiles. The FOAF-like 
Harmonise relation "relatedTo" between tourist entities is used to chain through Bhutan provinces 
and attraction profiles, hence to provide attraction-centric recommendations.
This prototype, eTourPlan, an eTourism planner using Semantic Web techniques, has been implemented 
in RuleML/POSL. Results of running eTourPlan in the prototype RuleML engine OO jDREW are reported.
</p>	
</section>

	<section>
		<header>Prototype</header>
		<p>The eTourPlan prototype -- its theory and implementation -- is described in detail in the documents below.
	   </p>
		<itemize>
			<item>eTourPlan: A Knowledge-Based Tourist Route and Activity Planner (Presentation): <a href="http://www.ruleml.org/usecases/etourplan/eTourPlanPresentation/">PPT</a></item>
			<item>eTourPlan: A Knowledge-Based Tourist Route and Activity Planner (Thesis): <a href="http://www.ruleml.org/usecases/etourplan/TsheringMCSThesis.pdf">PDF</a></item>			
			<item>eTourPlan KB (fact and rule profiles): <a href="http://www.ruleml.org/usecases/etourplan/eTourPlanKB.posl">POSL</a></item>
			<item>RDFS taxonomies (adapted from the Harmonise classification): <a href="http://www.ruleml.org/usecases/etourplan/RDFSTypeDefinitions">RDF</a></item>			
	</itemize>
	</section>
	<closing>
		<p>
		Site Contact:
		<a href="http://www.cs.unb.ca/~boley/">Harold Boley</a>.
		Page Version: 2008-09-16
		<br/>
			<br/>
			<br/>

			<a name="Practice-Preach"/>
			<small>"Practice what you preach": XML source of this homepage at <a href="index.xml">index.xml</a>;
	      <br/>
	      transformed to HTML via the adaptation of <a href="http://www.dfki.uni-kl.de/~sintek/">Michael Sintek</a>'s SliML <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xslt">XSLT</a> stylesheet at <a href="http://www.dfki.uni-kl.de/~boley/xslt/homepage.xsl">homepage.xsl</a> (View | Page Source)
	   </small>

		</p>
	</closing>
</homepage>
