<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.ruleml.org/homepage.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<!-- Written by Harold Boley -->

<homepage>

	<title>RestaurantFinderKB</title>

	<opening>
		<center>
			<br/>
<!--			<a href="http://www.ruleml.org"><img src="http://www.ruleml.org/logo/rulemllogo2_transparent.gif" border="none" alt="RuleML"/></a>
-->
			<br/>
			<h1>RestaurantFinderKB:<br/>Modeling Semantic Search in OO jDREW with an International-Cuisine Taxonomy</h1>
			<h2>Atteeka Rashid, William Ross, Girish Ranganathan, Bhanu Petchetti</h2>
			<h4>Version History, 2006-01-16: Version 0.5
			</h4><br/>
			<h2>Version History, 2006-01-16: Version 0.5
			</h2>
		</center>
		<br/>
		
		<p>This is a POSL use case of taxonomic and instance knowledge
		 describing numerous food items and 24 fictitious restaurants.
		 It has been developed using the OO jDREW rule engine.</p>
	</opening>
	
	
	<section>
		<header>Overview</header>
		<p>The goal of our project is to demonstrate how semantic searching might be accomplished.
		To this end, we have created a mini-web scenario of numerous food items and 24 fictitious restaurants,
		where each URI relates to one fictitious restaurant's homepage.
		Furthermore, we have simulated some features of RDF and RDFS using the <a href="http://www.ruleml.org/submission/ruleml-shortation.html">POSL</a> logic programming representation,
		and we have developed an international-cuisine taxonomy that we use to classify both restaurants and food dishes.
		We use the information from our fictitious mini-web, stored as facts in our knowledge base, along with facts and rules
		inferred by our taxonomy to model the semantic searching of restaurants and food dishes in <a href="http://www.jdrew.org/oojdrew/">OO jDREW</a>.
		Our hope was to gain some experience with tools used in Semantic Web development
		and to gain some knowledge regarding semantic searching, which we feel is an integral part of the Semantic Web.
		The project is fully described in a report
		(<a href="RestaurantFinderReport.pdf">RestaurantFinderReport.pdf</a>, <a href="RestaurantFinderReport.doc">RestaurantFinderReport.doc</a>)</p>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<header>RestaurantFinderKB in POSL Syntax</header>
                <p>The POSL source file: <a href="RestaurantFinderKB.posl">RestaurantFinderKB.posl</a></p>
	</section>
	
		
	<closing>
		<p>
		Site Contact:
		<a href="http://www.cs.unb.ca/~boley/">Harold Boley</a>.
		Page Version: 2006-01-16
		
		<br/>
		<br/>
		<br/>
		<a name="Practice-Preach"/>
		<small>"Practice what you preach": XML source of this homepage at <a href="index.xml">index.xml</a>;
	      <br/>
	      transformed to HTML via the adaptation of <a href="http://www.dfki.uni-kl.de/~sintek/">Michael Sintek</a>'s SliML <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xslt">XSLT</a> stylesheet at <a href="http://www.dfki.uni-kl.de/~boley/xslt/homepage.xsl">homepage.xsl</a> (View | Page Source)
	   </small>
		</p>
	</closing>
	
</homepage>
